A Guide to the Henry H. Douglas Collection, 1861-1978
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Henry H. Douglas Collection, 1861-1978
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 06-13
1.5 linear feet
The Henry H. Douglas Collection consists of 1.5 linear feet and spans the years 1861-1978. It contains correspondence, news articles, membership cards, meeting announcements, a transcription, photostats, photographs, negatives, and currency.
Henry H. Douglas (1906-1989)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Donated by the Estate of Henry H. Douglas in 1989.
Historical and Biographical Information
Henry Hulbert Douglas was born in a log cabin near Bozeman, Montana on February 27, 1906, to Emma Catherine and Elmer Allen Douglas. He attended Billings Polytechnic Institute, the University of Montana at Missoula, and graduated from Oberlin College in 1929. Douglas went on to serve as a librarian at the American Merchant Marine Library Association and later as a librarian at the Library of Congress in 1937.
In 1942, Douglas testified before the House Committee on Un-American Activities (Dies Committee) due to his association with the American League for Peace and Democracy in 1938 and the Washington Committee to Aid China in 1939. He denied being a communist and the committee ultimately cleared him.
On May 9, 1942, Douglas enlisted in the Army at Fort Myer, Virginia. He was stationed with the 6th Army Air Force at Albrook Field in Panama and later transferred to the Chinese Air Force Detachment at Tyndall Field in Florida serving as a Chinese interpreter.
After World War II, Douglas returned to the Library of Congress, later worked for the Office of Technical Services at the Department of Commerce, and went on to become a librarian for Mary Riley Styles Public Library in Falls Church, Virginia.
In 1960, Douglas established Econoprint, a printing business which he operated for twenty-one years. In 1967, Douglas founded the Pioneer America Society which published articles about historic sites in Northern Virginia. He was editor for the Society’s “Pioneer American” and “Echoes of History” journals. A long-time resident of Falls Church, he also served as the chairman of the Falls Church Historical Commission and was also the group’s historian and archivist. He and his wife, June Douglas, published the quarterly “Falls Church Historical News and Notes” from 1970-1972. In later years, Henry Douglas continued writing and editing “Falls Church Historical News and Notes” articles for The Falls Church News-Advertiser from 1980-1983.
Douglas authored a number of books including “Caves of Virginia” (1964); “Falls Church, Places and People” (1981) as well as edited and published the second edition of Herbert H. Harwood’s “Rail’s to the Blue Bridge” which included Douglas’ photos of rolling stock and scenes along the Washington & Old Dominion Railroad. Henry H. Douglas died on January 16, 1989.
Scope and Content
The Henry H. Douglas Collection consists of 1.5 linear feet and spans the years 1861-1978. It contains correspondence, news articles, membership cards, meeting announcements, a transcription, photostats, photographs, negatives, and currency. The bulk of the collection consists of negatives from Douglas’ publications “Echoes of History” and “Falls Church Historical News and Notes”. Subjects include historic sites in Northern Virginia; Falls Church, Virginia; and the Washington and Old Dominion Railroad.
Series 1: Personal Papers, 1861-1978, Box 1
This series contains correspondence, news articles, membership cards, meeting announcements from the Historical Society of Fairfax County, a “Dog Dollar” issued on September 24, 1861 in Leesburg, Virginia, and the original photostat copy of the 2nd edition of Herbert H. Harwood’s “Rails to the Blue Ridge”. Included are documents concerning Douglas’ testimony before the House Committee of Un-American Activities in 1942 including letters from Rep. Jerry Voorhis, attorneys, friends, and supporters. Also featured in this series is Henry and June Douglas’ transcription of "Report Concerning Removal of Gunpowder from the Naval Magazine During the British Invasion of Washington. Sept. 10, 1814-Sept. 10, 1815” which was written by Mordecai Booth who supervised the removal and subsequent return of gunpowder to Daniel Dulany’s farm in Falls Church, Virginia in 1814. Douglas’ correspondence concerning the Washington and Old Dominion Railroad, Fairfax County Historical Landmarks Preservation Commission, and Fairfax County History Commission is also contained here.
Series 2: Negatives
Sub-series 2-1: Publications, 1969-1975, Box 1
This series contains Washington & Old Dominion Railroad illustration negatives for the second edition of “Rails to the Blue Ridge” by Herbert H. Harwood (1969) and the print negatives and half-tone negatives for “Falls Church Celebrates 100 Years”(1975), a seventeen-page booklet about the history of Falls Church.
Sub-series 2-2: Echoes of History, 1968-1976, Box 2
This series contains negatives for the Pioneer America Society’s bi-monthly publication “Echoes of History”. It was published from 1970-1976 and featured articles about historic structures and places in Northern Virginia. The negatives are organized by the volume and issue number in which they were published except for larger negatives which are filed at the end. The volume, issue, and page number of where each illustration appeared in the journal are included in the description.
Sub-series 2-3: Falls Church Historical News and Notes, 1967-1973, Box 3
This series contains negatives for Henry and June Douglas’ quarterly publication “Falls Church Historical News and Notes”. It was published from 1970-1972 featuring articles about the history of Falls Church. The negatives are organized by the volume and issue number in which they were published except for larger negatives which are filed at the end. The volume, issue, and page number of where each illustration appeared in the journal are included in the description.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Photographs from this collection were integrated into the Fairfax County Public Library Photographic Archive. Other materials from Douglas’ estate were transferred to Alexandria Public Library, Prince William County Public Library, Thomas Balch Library and the Library of Virginia.
Index Terms
Douglas, Henry H. (1906-1989); Fairfax County (Va.) - Buildings, structures, etc.; Falls Church (Va.) - History; Historic buildings - Virginia; United States - Congress - House - Committee on Un-American Activities; Washington & Old Dominion Railroad
Container List
- Series 1: Personal Papers, 1861-1978
  - Leesburg, Va. “Dog Dollar”, Issued 1861, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - House Committee of Un-American Activities “Dies Committee”, Correspondence & News Clippings, 1939-1947 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Fairfax County Historical Landmarks Preservation Commission, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Fairfax County History Commission, 1969-1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Washington and Old Dominion Railroad, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Statement at East Falls Church Metro Station Design Hearing, April 25, 1972 [3 copies], 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Historical Society of Fairfax County. Announcements of Meetings & Membership Cards, 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Historical Society of Herndon. Constitution and Meeting Announcements, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - J. Berkley Green. List of Herndon Photographs and Funeral Home History, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - “Your Obedient Servant, Mordecai Booth” transcribed 1970 by June and H.H. Douglas, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - “Rails to the Blue Ridge” by Herbert Harwood, 2nd edition, 1969 [Original Photostat Copy], 1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Series 2: Negatives
  - Sub-series 2-1: Publications, 1969-1975
    - “Rails to the Blue Ridge” by Herbert Harwood, 2nd edition, 1969 [Original half-tone illustration negatives], 1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - “Falls Church Celebrates 100 Years” Master Print Negatives and Half-tone negatives, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Sub-series 2-2: Echoes of History, 1968-1976
    - Braden-Roberts Log House (v.1, no.1, p.1), Undated (Box 2)
    - Funeral Procession in Herndon, Va., towards Chestnut Grove Cemetery (v.1, no.1, p.4), Undated (Box 2)
    - Hume School, Arlington Historical Society Headquarters (v.1, no.1, p.5), Undated (Box 2)
    - Heard in Loudon County (v.1, no.1, p.6), Undated (Box 2)
    - Green Spring Farm (v.1, no.1, p.7), Undated (Box 2)
    - Mount Air (v.1, no.1, p.8), Undated (Box 2)
    - Mohler House, Front Façade (v.1, no.1, p.9), Undated (Box 2)
    - Mohler House, Rear Façade (v.1, no.1, p.10), Undated (Box 2)
    - View with Mohler House and Centreville Methodist Church (v.1, no.1, p.11), Undated (Box 2)
    - View with Mohler House and Main St. (v.1, no.1, p.11), Undated (Box 2)
    - Dranesville Tavern (v.1, no.1, p.12), Undated (Box 2)
    - Maplewood, West Elevation (v.1, no.1, p.13), Undated (Box 2)
    - Chestnut Grove (v.1, no.1, p.14), Undated (Box 2)
    - Occoquan Iron Bridge, Facing West (v.1, no.1, p.15), Undated (Box 2)
    - Sudley Mansion (v.1, no.1, p.16), Undated (Box 2)
    - View of Occoquan (v.1, no.2, p.17), Undated (Box 2)
    - Washington, Alexandria, and Mt. Vernon Railroad Parlor Car No. 15 (v.1, no.2, p.20), Undated (Box 2)
    - Interior of Roof of Ravensworth Barn (v.1 no.2, p.21), Undated (Box 2)
    - Ravensworth Barn (v.1, no.2, p.21), Undated (Box 2)
    - Fairfaview Barns and Silo (v.1, no.2, p.22), Undated (Box 2)
    - Fairview Farmhouse (v.1 no.2, p.22), Undated (Box 2)
    - Hayfield Barn (v.1, no.2, p.22), Undated (Box 2)
    - Big Rock (Hertz House) (v.1, no.2, p.26), Undated (Box 2)
    - Bel Air (v.1, no.2, p.28), Undated (Box 2)
    - Bell on East Side of Bel Air (v.1, no.2, p.28), Undated (Box 2)
    - Drawing Room, Bel Air (v.1, no.2, p.28), Undated (Box 2)
    - Rockledge (v.1, no.2, p.29), Undated (Box 2)
    - Rockledge, Front Steps to Elizabeth Street (v.1, no.2, p.29), Undated (Box 2)
    - Lower Dam and Head of Mill Race on Occoquan River, Looking Upstream (v.1, no.2, p.30), Undated (Box 2)
    - The Clark (v.1, no.2, p.31), Undated (Box 2)
    - Large Barn at Little Sully (v.1, no.3, p.33), Undated (Box 2)
    - Fire at Herbert Bryant Fire (v.1, no.3, p.34), Undated (Box 2)
    - Herbert Bryant Fertilizer Plant (v.1, no.3, p.34), Undated (Box 2)
    - Beall-Dawson House, Rockville, Maryland (v.1, no.3, p.37), Undated (Box 2)
    - Falls Church Railway Station No. 2 (v.1, no.3, p.40), Undated (Box 2)
    - Hope Farm, 3701 Chain Bridge Rd., Fairfax, Va. (v.1, no.3, p.41), Undated (Box 2)
    - Minor Barlow House (v.1, no.3, p.42), Undated (Box 2)
    - 8008 North Park St., Dunn Loring (v.1, no.3, p.44), Undated (Box 2)
    - Pearson's Store and Newington Post Office (v.1, no.3, p.45), Undated (Box 2)
    - Newington Station (v.1, no.3, p.45), Undated (Box 2)
    - Nachman's Store and Herndon Post Office (v.1, no.3, p.46), Undated (Box 2)
    - Eldon Street Looking West (v.1 no.3 p.46), Undated (Box 2)
    - Washington and Old Dominion Station (v.1, no.3, p.47), Undated (Box 2)
    - Little Sully House Foundations (v.1, no.3, p.49), Undated (Box 2)
    - The House at Little Sully (v.1, no.3, p.49), Undated (Box 2)
    - Barn at Little Sully (v.1, no.3, p.50), Undated (Box 2)
    - The Nelson House (v.1, no.3, p.52), Undated (Box 2)
    - The Ben Lomond House (v.1, no.4, p.53), Undated (Box 2)
    - Ben Lomond Barn (v.1, no.4, p.55), Undated (Box 2)
    - Ball's Ford Furniture Factory (v.1, no.4, p.55), Undated (Box 2)
    - Sunny Brook Dairy Barn, Sudley Road, Manassas (v.1, no.4, p.55), Undated (Box 2)
    - Manassas Southern Railway Station (rebuilt) (v.1, no.4, p.56), Undated (Box 2)
    - The Seoane House with Addition (v.1, no.4, p.56), Undated (Box 2)
    - The Seoane House, Side Elevation (v.1, no.4, p.57), Undated (Box 2)
    - Clay Cook, Seoane Caretaker, In Front of His Home (v.1, no.4, p.57), Undated (Box 2)
    - Clay Cook's Boudoir in Barn Loft (v.1, no.4, p.58), Undated (Box 2)
    - Clay Cook's Second Home at Seoane Place (v.1, no.4, p.58), Undated (Box 2)
    - Seoane Place, Partially Demolished (v.1, no.4, p.58), Undated (Box 2)
    - Oak Tree (Oakton's Namesake) (v.1, no.4, p.59), Undated (Box 2)
    - Clay Cook's Second Home, Demolished (v.1, no.4, p.59), Undated (Box 2)
    - Clay Cook's Second Home and Well House at Seoane Place (v.1, no.4, p.59), Undated (Box 2)
    - The Seoane Barns (v.1, no.4, p.59), Undated (Box 2)
    - Willoughby Newton Boundary Stone (v.1, no.4, p.61), Undated (Box 2)
    - Cleo (v.1, no.4, p.61), Undated (Box 2)
    - Alexander Haight (v.1, no.4, p.62), Undated (Box 2)
    - George Curry at Little Sully (v.1, no.2, p.62), Undated (Box 2)
    - Mountain View, Front and Side Elevations 1936 (v.1, no.4, p.63), Undated (Box 2)
    - Mountain View, Side (Bull Run Post Office Road) Elevation 1936 (v.1, no.4, p.63), Undated (Box 2)
    - Mountain View, Side (Bull Run Post Office Road) Elevation 1958(v.1, no.4, p.64), Undated (Box 2)
    - Mountain View, Side (Bull Run Post Office Road) Elevation 1969 (v.1, no.2, p.64), Undated (Box 2)
    - Mountain View, Side Elevation 1969 (v.1, no.4, p.65), Undated (Box 2)
    - Mountain View After December 1970 Fire (v.1, no.4, p.65), Undated (Box 2)
    - Mountain View, Side Elevation, After December 1970 Fire (v.1, no.4, p.66), Undated (Box 2)
    - Lakeland c. 1967 (v.1, no.4, p.67), Undated (Box 2)
    - Lakeland Slave Quarters (v.1, no.4, p.67), Undated (Box 2)
    - Beverley Mill, c. 1970 (v.1, no.5, p.67), Undated (Box 2)
    - St. John's Church, Centreville (v.1, no.5, p.73), Undated (Box 2)
    - Gravestone of Jacob Wright, Flint Hill Cemetery (v1, no.5, p.73), Undated (Box 2)
    - Monument to Mary J. Marshall, Marshall Family Cemetery (v.1, no.5, p.74), Undated (Box 2)
    - Henry Peake Gravestone, Peake Family Burial Ground (v.1, no.5, p.74), Undated (Box 2)
    - Dulin House, Graham Road, Falls Church (v.1, no.5, p.75), Undated (Box 2)
    - Largest American Elm in Virginia, 2447 Gallows Road (v.1 no.5, p.76), Undated (Box 2)
    - Bill Barrett, Photographer (v.1, no.5, p.76), Undated (Box 2)
    - Earp's Ordinary, (v.1, no.5, p.77), Undated (Box 2)
    - Colvin Run Mill (v.1, no.5, p.77), Undated (Box 2)
    - Colvin Run Mill, Main Entrance (v.1, no.5 p.78), Undated (Box 2)
    - Colvin Run Mill, Drawing by Polly Beverley (v.1, no.5, p.78), Undated (Box 2)
    - Mill Wheel, Colvin Run Mill West Elevation (v.1, no.5, p.79), Undated (Box 2)
    - Colvin Run Mill, North and East Elevations (v.1, no.5, p.80), Undated (Box 2)
    - Beverley Mill, Rear View (v.1, no.5, p.80), Undated (Box 2)
    - Chapman Stone? (negative missing, p. 81), Undated (Box 2)
    - Beverley Mill, North Elevation (v.1, no.5, p.81), Undated (Box 2)
    - Meadowlands (Chapman House) Ruins (v.1, no.5, p.82), Undated (Box 2)
    - Broad Run Post Office (v.1, no.5, p.83), Undated (Box 2)
    - Broad Run Post Office, Rear View (v.1, no.5, p.83), Undated (Box 2)
    - Beverley Mill Bag (v.1 no.5, p.84), Undated (Box 2)
    - Millbrook Ruins (v.1, no. 5, p.84), Undated (Box 2)
    - Millbrook Gateposts, Rt. 600 (v.1, no.5, p.84), Undated (Box 2)
    - Phoebe Sweet Haight (v.1, no. 6, p.85), Undated (Box 2)
    - Alexander Haight (v.1, no.6, p.85), Undated (Box 2)
    - Ossian Hall Burn (v.1, no.6, p.90), Undated (Box 2)
    - Ossian Hall, North Elevation (v.1, no.6, p.90), Undated (Box 2)
    - Interior Stairway, Ossian Hall (v.1, no.6, p.91), Undated (Box 2)
    - Fireplace, Ossian Hall (v.1, no.6, p.91), Undated (Box 2)
    - Fireplace with Mantel, Ossian Hall (v.1, no.6, p.92), Undated (Box 2)
    - 1805 Insurance Declaration for Ossian Hall (v.1, no.6, p. 92), Undated (Box 2)
    - Ossian Hall, South and West Elevations (v.1, no. 6, p.93), Undated (Box 2)
    - Thomas Viaduct, B&O Railroad (v.1, no.6, p.93), Undated (Box 2)
    - Legato School (Early in Restoration) (v.1, no.6, p.94), Undated (Box 2)
    - Legato School (Late in Restoration) (v.1, no.6, p94), Undated (Box 2)
    - House in Fairfax City, Location Unknown (v.1, no.6, p.95), Undated (Box 2)
    - Baltimore Livestock Exchange (v.1, no.6, p.95), Undated (Box 2)
    - The Maples (Porter House) (v.1, no.6, p.95), Undated (Box 2)
    - Group in Front of The Maples (Porter Home) (v.1, no. 6, p.96), Undated (Box 2)
    - Dranesville Tavern, South Elevation (negative missing, p.97), Undated (Box 2)
    - Dranesville Tavern During Restoration (v.1, no.7, p.99), Undated (Box 2)
    - Dranesville Tavern, South Elevation (v.1, no.7, p.99), Undated (Box 2)
    - Store at Dranesville Tavern (v.1, no.7, p.100), Undated (Box 2)
    - Dranesville Tavern, South Elevation (v.1, no.7, p.100), Undated (Box 2)
    - Rear Wing of Kitchen, Dranesville Tavern (v.1, no.7, p.101), Undated (Box 2)
    - Rear Hallway, Dranesville Tavern (v.1, no.7, p.101), Undated (Box 2)
    - Interior Hallway and Staircase Dranesville Tavern (v.1, no.7, p.102), Undated (Box 2)
    - Interior Staircase, Dranesville Tavern (v.1, no.7, p.102), Undated (Box 2)
    - Dranesville Tavern, South and East Elevations (v.1, no.7, p.103), Undated (Box 2)
    - Oakton's Namesake, Chain Bridge Rd and Hunter Mill Rd (v.1, no. 7, p. 103), Undated (Box 2)
    - Fourteen car "Steam Spectacular" (v.1, no7, p.103), Undated (Box 2)
    - Engine 750 (v.1, no. 7, p.105), Undated (Box 2)
    - Fairfax Station, 1968 (v.1, no.7, p.105), Undated (Box 2)
    - Clifton Hotel, Built 1876 (v.1, no.7, p.106), Undated (Box 2)
    - Manassas Station (v.1, no.7, p.106), Undated (Box 2)
    - Gainsville (v.1, no.7, p.106), Undated (Box 2)
    - Former Thoroughfare Station, west of Rt. 55, Undated (Box 2)
    - Broad Run Station (v.1, no.7, p.107), Undated (Box 2)
    - Belle Meade Distillery (v.1, no.7, p.107), Undated (Box 2)
    - Linden Station (v.1, no.7, p.108), Undated (Box 2)
    - Front Royal (v.1, no.7, p.108), Undated (Box 2)
    - Cornerstone Park, 1972 (v.2, no.1, p.1), Undated (Box 2)
    - Moorefield, 1972 (v.2, no.1, p.5), Undated (Box 2)
    - Spring Bank, Facade and Rear Wing (v.2, no.1, p.6), Undated (Box 2)
    - The McAtee Oak, 1971 (v.2, no.1, p.7), Undated (Box 2)
    - Cumberland Station with Queen City Hotel, Cumberland, Maryland (v.2, no.1, p.8), Undated (Box 2)
    - Ornamental Cast Ironwork, Queen City Hotel, Cumberland, Maryland (v.2, no.1, p.8), Undated (Box 2)
    - Brown's Mill at Beulah Road and Wolf Trap Creek (v.2, no.1, p.9), Undated (Box 2)
    - Brown's Mill, c. 1900 (v.2, no.1, p.9), Undated (Box 2)
    - Andrew Chapel School (v.2, no.1, p.10), Undated (Box 2)
    - Brown House, 1922 (v.2, no.1, p.11), Undated (Box 2)
    - Mr. and Mrs. William Everett Brown, 1920 (v.2, no.1, p.11), Undated (Box 2)
    - Weston, Casanova, Fauquier County, 1971 (v.2, no.1, p.12), Undated (Box 2)
    - Weston Interior, Casanova, Fauquier County, 1971 (v.2, no.1, p.12), Undated (Box 2)
    - Weston Kitchen Interior, Casanova, Fauquier County, 1971 (v.2, no.1, p.13), Undated (Box 2)
    - Brenzier House (v.2, no.1, p.14), Undated (Box 2)
    - West Cornerstone, Cornerstone Park (v.2, no1, p.14), 1972 (Box 2)
    - Falls Church Jurisdiction Stone No. 9, Van Buren St and Four Mile Run (v.2, no.1, p.16), Undated (Box 2)
    - Milk House at Weston (v.2, nos.2/3, p.17), 1970 (Box 2)
    - Corn Crib at Weston (v.2, nos. 2/3, p.19), 1970 (Box 2)
    - Bellows in Blacksmith Shop at Weston (v.2, nos.2/3, p.20), 1971 (Box 2)
    - Robert Edward Wagstaff, Lorraine Cross (left), and Virginia Weeks at Sully Mansion (v.2, no2/3, p.21), Undated (Box 2)
    - House on Cooke Row, Georgetown (v.2, no.2/3, p.22), Undated (Box 2)
    - Right Downstairs Front Room Mantel, Spring Bank (v.2, no.2/3, p.23), Undated (Box 2)
    - Wakefield Chapel (v.2, no.2/3, p.24), 1969 (Box 2)
    - Wakefield Chapel (v.2, no.2/3, p.24), 1969 (Box 2)
    - Furr House (v.2, no2/3, p.26), 1972 (Box 2)
    - Chapman Mill Ruins (v.2, no.2/3, p.27), 1972 (Box 2)
    - Chapman Mill Ruins (v.2, no2/3, p.27), 1972 (Box 2)
    - Ernest E. Webb (v.2, no2/3, p.28), 1972 (Box 2)
    - Fairfax County Courthouse, 1920s (v.2, no.2/3, p.30), Undated (Box 2)
    - Peyton Anderson Monument, White House Motel (v.2, no.2/3, p.30), Undated (Box 2)
    - Jacob and Amy Haight, c. 1840 (v. 2, no.2/3, p.32), Undated (Box 2)
    - Murtagh Cabin (v.1, no.2/3, p.32), Undated (Box 2)
    - Alexander Haight (v.2, no2/3, p.33), Undated (Box 2)
    - Sketch of Earp's Ordinary (v.2, no2/3, p.37), Undated (Box 2)
    - Avenel House (v.2, no.2/3, p.38), Undated (Box 2)
    - Fauquier County Court House (v.2, no.4, p.41), 1970 (Box 2)
    - Black Horse House (v.2, no.4, p. 43), 1970 (Box 2)
    - St. John's Catholic Church (v.2, no.4, p.44), 1970 (Box 2)
    - Warren Green Hotel (v.2, no.4, p.44), 1970 (Box 2)
    - Privado, 1958. (v.2, no.4, p.46), Undated (Box 2)
    - Wunder Home (v.2, no.4, p.47), 1971 (Box 2)
    - Moores Store Post Office Museum (v.2, no.4, p.48), Undated (Box 2)
    - "Thunder Shower" Mill (v.2, no.4, p.49), 1971 (Box 2)
    - Showalter Log Home / Village Museum and Handcraft Shoppe (v.2, no.4, p.49), 1971 (Box 2)
    - Miller's House, Moores Store Village (v.2, no.4, p.50), 1971 (Box 2)
    - The Castle, Pi Beta Nu, National Park Seminary (v.2, no.4, p.53), 1972 (Box 2)
    - The Pagoda, Chi Psi Upsilon, National Park Seminary (v.2, no.4, p.53), 1972 (Box 2)
    - National Park Seminary Map (v.2, no.4, p.54), Undated (Box 2)
    - The Swiss Chalet, Zeta Eta Theta, National Park Seminary (v.2, no.4, p.54), 1972 (Box 2)
    - Gymnasium, National Park Seminary (v.2, no.4, p.54), 1972 (Box 2)
    - Occoquan Iron Bridge during Flood, June 22, 1972 (v.2, no.4, p.55), 1972 June 22 (Box 2)
    - Occoquan Iron Bridge (v.2, no.4, p.55), 1970 (Box 2)
    - Edgar Shreve (v.2, no.5, p.57), 1972 July 31 (Box 2)
    - John Singleton Mosby (v.2, no.5, p.58), Undated (Box 2)
    - Stover's (Trap Branch) Mill, Fauquier County (v.2, no.5, p.60), 1969 (Box 2)
    - Jackson House, McLean, 1961. (v.2, no.5, p.66), Undated (Box 2)
    - Marshall House, Alexandria, in 1861 (v.2, no.5, p.67), Undated (Box 2)
    - Sketch of the Murder of Col. Ellsworth of the Fire Zouaves, Undated (Box 2)
    - Captain James W. Jackson / Gravestone of Jane Donaldson Jackson, 1961 (v.2, no.5, p.68 [2 negatives]), Undated (Box 2)
    - Confederate Veterans of Marr Camp, Fairfax, in 1928 or 1929 (v.2, no.5, p.69), Undated (Box 2)
    - Mount Gilead in 1909 / Mount Gilead in 1970 (v.2, no.5, p.70 [2 negatives]), Undated (Box 2)
    - Plan of Mount Pleasant (v.2, no.6, p.75), Undated (Box 2)
    - Anne Gotthardt at Mt. Pleasant in 1948 / Betty Stenhouse at Mt. Pleasant in 1948 (v.2, no.6, p.76 [2 negatives]), Undated (Box 2)
    - Front of Mt. Pleasant in 1912 (v.2, no.6, p.77), Undated (Box 2)
    - Rear of Mt. Pleasant in 1912 / Mt. Pleasant in 1957 (v.2, no.6, p.78 [2 negatives]), Undated (Box 2)
    - Gravestone for Robert S. Porter and Camille H. Porter (v.2, no.6, p.79), Undated (Box 2)
    - Edgar Shreve in 1972 / Judge Robert Grove Porter (1970) / Seoane House, Merrifield, in 1969 (v.2, no.6, p.80 [3 negatives]), 1970; 1972 (Box 2)
    - Frank Romine Taylor in 1924 / "The Lower Station", Dunn Loring (1960) / "The Upper Station", Dunn Loring (1971) (v.2, no.6, p.81 [3 negatives]), Undated (Box 2)
    - Gravestone of Tobias E. Robey and Lucy A. Robey, Merrifield Cemetery (v.2, no.6, p.82), Undated (Box 2)
    - Towne Carter House on Gallows Road (v.2, no.6, p.83), 1971 (Box 2)
    - Gravestone of Joseph Ashby Kidwell, Della E. Porter Kidwell, and Carrie Camilla Kidwell, Merrifield Cemetery (v.2, no.6, p.84), Undated (Box 2)
    - Bailey's Crossroads School (v.2, no.6, p.86), 1968 (Box 2)
    - Alexandria Canal (v.3, no.1, p.5), 1968 (Box 2)